**JavaScript seems to be disabled in your browser.** For the best experience on our site, be sure to turn on Javascript in your browser.

**Free Shipping on $199+ Orders**

Search  Search

x

Search  Search

My Cart
-------

loader

Loading...

Close panel

1. [Home](https://sdbullion.com/ "Go to Home Page")
2. chevron-right Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
==============

Effective Date: October 3, 2023

****Introduction****
--------------------

Welcome and thank you for visiting a website operated by SD Bullion, Inc (“SD Bullion, us, we, our”). We at SD Bullion, Inc take the privacy of all visitors to our websites very seriously. This Privacy Notice (“Notice”) informs you how we handle privacy matters and process your Personal Information. For the purpose of this Notice, "Personal Information" means any Personal Information relating to an identified or identifiable individual. We obtain Personal Information relating to you from various sources described below. “Services” means any and all use of our website(s) whether operated by SD Bullion, Inc or on our behalf.

****Scope****
-------------

This Notice applies to the SD Bullion, Inc’s website, sdbullion.com (“Site”), and all Personal Information that is shared when you visit the Site or interact with our Services. By using the Site, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Notice. 

****Information We Collect****
------------------------------

Through our Site and our Services, we may receive information that, alone or in combination with other information, could be used to identify an individual. We may receive information (including Personal Information) in the following ways:

### **Information That You Provide to Us**

When you request information from SD Bullion, Inc or interact with Services, we may receive the following Personal Information from you:

* Name
* Title
* Company name
* Billing address
* Shipping address
* Telephone number
* Email address
* Payment information
* Transaction History

### **Information Automatically Collected**

Like many businesses, we and/or our service providers may automatically collect and/or store certain information when you visit or interact with the Site. This information may be stored and/or accessed from your personal computer, laptop, tablet, mobile phone or other device whenever you visit or interact with our Site. Usage Information may include:

* Your IP address, IDFA, Android/Google Advertising ID, IMEI, or another unique identifier;
* Your device functionality (including browser, browser language, operating system, hardware, mobile network information);
* Referring and exit web pages and URLs; 
* The areas within the Site that you visit and your activities there, including remembering you and your preferences;
* Your device location or other geolocation information, including the zip code, state or country from which you accessed the Services;
* Your device characteristics; and
* Certain other device data, including the time of day you visit our Site or other information used to provide analytics or other usage information.

### **Information Collected by Third Parties**

The Site may include functionality that allows certain kinds of interactions between the Site and your account on a third-party website or application. The use of this functionality may involve the third-party site providing information to us. For example, we might obtain information about the traffic and usage of the Site from third parties. We might also provide links to facilitate sending a communication from the Site, or we may use third parties to facilitate emails or postings to social media (like a “Share” or “Forward” button). These third parties also use cookies and other tracking technologies to capture information about your interactions with the Site. We do not have control over the information that is collected, used, and shared by these third parties. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of these third parties to understand their privacy practices.

### **Communications**

When you send email or other communications to SD Bullion, Inc, we may keep those communications to process your questions, respond to your requests and improve our Site. We may use your email address to communicate with you about our Services.

****How We Use Information Collected****
----------------------------------------

We may use your Personal Information for the following business purposes:

1. To provide the products and Services you requested or bought from us.
2. To enhance our products and Services. 
3. To evaluate your application for employment.
4. To operate, maintain, and provide features of the Services.
5. To respond to comments and questions, and otherwise to provide support to users.
6. To understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our users.
7. To improve the Services, and to develop new products, services, features, and functionality.
8. To contact you for administrative and informational purposes. This may include providing customer service or sending communications, including changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.
9. For marketing purposes, such as developing and providing promotional and advertising materials including SMS promotions (if opted in) and sweepstakes opportunities that may be useful, relevant or valuable.
10. For our business purposes, such as audits, security, compliance with our internal policies, license agreements with content providers, applicable laws and regulations, fraud and financial crime monitoring and prevention.
11. To enforce our [Terms of Use](https://sdbullion.com/terms-use) or other legal rights.

****Use Of Cookies****
----------------------

We use “cookies” (small text files sent by your computer each time you visit our Site) and other tracking technologies to personalize your experience, analyze user trends, and improve the Services. These tracking technologies allow us to collect information such as your device type, browser type, interactions with our Site, geographic location, your web request, the date and time of your web request, your Internet Protocol address, the domain name of your Internet service provider and other data. 

You can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse to accept cookies, but it is possible that doing so may cause limited functionality of the Site. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer or device, and you may need to log in every time you visit. [Read more here.](https://sdbullion.com/cookie-policy)

We may use cookies or similar technologies to record log data. Many browsers default to accepting cookies. You may be able to change this setting in your browser and you can also clear your cookies. If you do, you may lose some functionality of our site. Check your browser’s help function to learn more about your cookie setting options. 

We may use the following types of cookies:

* Advertising and analytics 
* Essential cookies 
* Functionality cookies 
* Social Media cookies

We might also use a pixel tag which is a small graphic file that allows us and third parties to monitor the use of the Site and provide us with information based on your interaction with the Site. These tags may collect the IP address from the device which you loaded the page, the browser type. Pixel tags are also used by our third parties to collect information when you visit our site, the links and other actions you take on our Site, and we may use this information in combination with cookies to display targeted advertisements.

Other data technologies may be used that collect comparable information for security and fraud detection purposes.

If you have any questions about cookies or to generally find out more about cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org/. 

****How We Share Your Personal Information****
----------------------------------------------

We may share your Personal Information as follows:

* With our affiliates and subsidiaries for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice.
* With business partners or advertising partners to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you. 
* With our third-party service providers who provide services such as website hosting, data analysis, information technology and related infrastructure provision, fraud prevention, secure payment processing, customer service, email delivery, auditing, and other Services.
* With a potential or actual acquirer, successor, or assignee as part of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
* If required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities, including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

We may also share Personal Information about you with other third parties without your permission. We may use and disclose aggregate information that does not identify or otherwise relate to an individual for any purpose, unless we are prohibited from doing so under applicable law.

****Security****
----------------

SD Bullion, Inc has developed or engaged technical and organization measures designed to protect Personal Information against unauthorized access or misuse. However, the Internet cannot be guaranteed to be fully secure and we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you provide to us. We do not accept liability for unintentional disclosure. 

****International Transfers Of Data****
---------------------------------------

This Site is operated in the United States. If you are located in another jurisdiction, please know that your information will be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States. By using this Site and providing us with information, you consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States. It is important to note that the privacy laws in the United States may not be as comprehensive as those in other countries such as those in the European Union (“EU”). Our service providers use appropriate safeguards to transfer your Personal Information to the United States.

**Your Rights Under The General Data Protection Regulation**
------------------------------------------------------------

We have listed below the rights that you may be able to exercise in respect of the processing of your Personal Information, subject to applicable law. We take every reasonable step to ensure that the Personal Information that we process is limited to the Personal Information that is reasonably required in connection with the purposes set out in this Privacy Notice.

If you are a resident of or located within the EEA, you have the following data protection rights:

* The right to access or update the information we have collected from you. Whenever made possible, you can access, update your Personal Information by contacting us at the contact information below. 
* The right of rectification. You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.
* The right to object. You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Information.
* The right of restriction. You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your Personal Information.
* The right to data portability. You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable, and commonly used format.
* The right to withdraw consent. You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where we relied on your consent to process your Personal Information.

In most instances, SD Bullion, Inc is the data controller for processing Personal Information provided to us through the Site. 

### **Legal Basis for Processing Personal Information**

We rely on the following legal bases for processing your Personal Information:

* **To conclude or perform a contract with you.**

* To process your purchases of or requests for products and Services.
* To communicate with you about orders, purchases, returns, services, accounts, programs, contests, and sweepstakes.

* **For our legitimate business purposes**.

* To respond to your customer service inquiries and requests for information.
* To maintain, improve, and analyze our Site, mobile applications, ads, and the products and services we offer.
* To detect, prevent, or investigate security breaches or fraud.
* To facilitate the functionality of our websites and mobile applications.

* **To comply with our legal obligations.**

* To maintain appropriate records for internal administrative purposes and as required by applicable law, and provide important product safety information and notice of product recalls.

* **On the basis of your consent.**

* To send you via email and other electronic means personalized promotions and special offers or informing you about our products, Services, events, or other promotional purposes.
* You can withdraw your consent at any time by clicking the unsubscribe option in any promotional email, or by contacting us as described in the Contact Us section below.

### **Retention of Personal Information**

SD Bullion, Inc will retain your Personal Information only for as long as necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Notice. We will retain and use your Personal Information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers or those of our third-party data storage providers.

### **Exercising Your Rights Under GDPR**

If applicable, you may exercise any of your rights under the GDPR by submitting a verifiable data subject request to us by using the contact details below. You may make a request related to your Personal Information or on behalf of someone for which you have authorization. You must include your full name, email address, and attest to the fact that you are a citizen or resident of the EEA by including your country of citizenship or residence in your request. We may require you to confirm your identity and/or legal standing for the request as well as your residency in the EEA in order to obtain the information. 

Please note that we will ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests, and we may deny your request if we are unable to verify your identity or authority to make the request.

SD Bullion, Inc  
PO Box 8766

Toledo, OH 43623

**Email:** sales@sdbullion.com 

**Phone:** 1(800)294-8732

****Your California Privacy Rights****
--------------------------------------

If you are a California resident, you may be able to exercise the following rights. We will honor requests received to the extent required by applicable law and within the time provided by law.

### **Your Rights**

California residents have the following rights:

* **Right to access.** You have the right to request that we disclose the following to you, in each case in the twelve-month period preceding your request:

* Categories of Personal Information we have collected about you;
* Categories of sources from which the Personal Information is collected;
* Our business or commercial purpose for collecting Personal Information; 
* Categories of third parties with whom we share Personal Information; 
* Specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about you;
* Categories of Personal Information about you, if any, that we have disclosed for monetary or other valuable consideration and the categories of third parties to which we have disclosed the information, by category or categories of Personal Information for each third party to which we disclosed the Personal Information; and
* Categories of Personal Information about you that we disclosed for a business purpose.

* ****Right to delete:** If applicable by Federal law**

* **Right to correct**

* **Right to opt-out**. You have the right to opt out of the sale or sharing of Personal Information. We do not sell Personal Information, but we recognize that some privacy laws define “personal information” in such a way that making available identifiers linked to you for a benefit may be considered a “sale.” To learn more, please [click here](https://sdbullion.com/notice-of-right-to-opt-out).
* **Right to Limit the Use or Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information.** We do not use Sensitive Personal Information for reasons other than those listed in the CCPA. 

* **Right to Non-Discrimination.** We may not discriminate against you because you have exercised any of the aforementioned rights, including by denying you goods or services; charging different prices or rates for goods or services; providing you a different level or quality of goods or services; or suggesting that you will receive different price or rate for goods or service or at a different level or quality of goods or services. We also cannot retaliate against current and prospective employees for exercising their CCPA rights.

However, we may offer you certain financial incentives. Any CCPA-permitted financial incentive we offer will reasonably relate to your Personal Information’s value. Participation in a financial incentive program requires your prior opt-in consent, which you may withdraw at any time.

### **Personal** **Information** **We** **Collect** **about** **California** **Consumers**

We collect certain types of Personal Information about you during your relationship with us, as stated above. In particular, we collected the following categories of Personal Information from California consumers within the last twelve (12) months:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of Personal Information Collected** | **Collected (Yes/No)** | **Sources of Personal Information Collected** |
| Identifiers such as name, address, email address, phone number, unique id, and other identifiers listed above. | Yes | You |
| The following categories of Personal Information described in California Civil Code §1798.80(e): (1) the Personal Information listed in the preceding bullet point as “identifiers,” and (2) the other information that identifies, relates to, describes, or is capable of being associated with a particular individual that we describe in “Information We Collect” above. | Yes | You |
| Characteristics of protected classifications under California or federal law list any of these that you collect: race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status. | No  | N/A |
| Commercial information, including information about orders or purchases of any of our products or services; registration information, specials, and information you provide or submit to us when you participate in any event, program, contest, survey or other promotion that we may offer from time to time. | Yes | You |
| Biometric Information. | No  | N/A |
| Internet or other electronic network activity information, including, but not limited to, information regarding your interaction with our websites, mobile apps, or Company pages or accounts on any third-party social media platforms. | Yes | Automatically<br><br>Third Parties |
| Geolocation data. | Yes | You<br><br>Automatically<br><br>Third Parties |
| Audio information from calls placed with customer service and accounting centers which may be reported, and electronic information in the form of Internet or other electronic network activity information described above. | Yes | You<br><br>Automatically |
| Professional or employment-related information. | No  | N/A |
| Education information. | No  | N/A |
| Inferences drawn from (1) the information we collect when you visit our websites, tools, widgets and plug-ins, (2) information we collect, including through third-party suppliers, regarding content and other data posted on the Internet (such as public locations on the Internet), and (3) information about consumers preference and behavior that we collect on our websites and mobile apps or purchase from third parties in order to create a profile about a consumer reflecting the consumer’s preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities and aptitudes. | Yes | You<br><br>Automatically<br><br>Third Parties |
| Sensitive Personal Information such as email and text message content, driver’s license, state identification card, account login, financial account, debit card, or credit card number. | Yes | You |

### **How to Exercise Your California Privacy Rights**

You or your authorized agent may make a request to access, correct, delete or opt-out of the disclosure of your Personal Information for business purposes. You may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child if you believe we have received their information inadvertently. You may request to exercise the aforementioned rights by:

* Submitting a request to [sales@sdbullion.com](mailto:sales@sdbullion.com)
* Calling this toll free number 1(800)294-8732

Please note that we may take steps to verify your identity and residency before granting you access to information or acting on your request to exercise your rights, as required or permitted by law. This might include asking for your email address or other personal, verifiable information.

If you use an authorized agent to exercise your rights, we may require proof of written authorization you have given the authorized agent to make the request on your behalf. 

### **Data Sharing for Direct Marketing Purposes**

California Civil Code § 1798.83 further permits California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident, you may ask us to refrain from sharing your Personal Information with certain of our affiliates and other third parties for their marketing purposes. Please tell us your preference by contacting us at sales@sdbullion.com.

****Your Virginia Privacy Rights****
------------------------------------

If you are a resident of Virginia, you have the right under the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act, upon a verified request, to:

* To confirm whether or not a controller is processing your personal data and to access such personal data;
* To correct inaccuracies in your personal data;
* To delete your personal data if applicable by Federal law;
* To obtain a copy of your personal data that you previously provided to us in a portable, and if technically feasible, readily usable format, if processing is carried out by automated means;
* To opt out of the processing of your personal data for purposes of (i) targeted advertising, (ii) the sale of personal data, or (iii) profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning the consumer. 

To exercise these rights, you may make a request to confirm, access, correct, delete, obtain a copy, or opt-out of the processing of your personal data for targeting advertising, sale, or profiling by contacting us using the information in the Contact Us section below:

We may require you to confirm your identity and your residency in order to obtain the information, and you are only entitled to make this request up to twice annually. For emails, please include “Virginia Privacy Rights” as the subject line. You must include your full name, email address, and attest to the fact that you are a Virginia resident. We will process your request within 45 days or let you know if we need additional time or cannot process your request. If you make this request by telephone, we may also ask you to provide the request in writing so that we may verify your identity. If we are unable to honor your request for any reason, we will notify you of the reason within the request time period.

If we decline to take action on your request, residents of Virginia can appeal our decision by submitting an email to sales@sdbullion.com entitled “Virginia Privacy Rights Appeal” and we will review your request and respond with a written explanation of the reasons for our decision. If your appeal is denied, you may contact the [Virginia Attorney General](https://www.virginia.gov/agencies/office-of-the-attorney-general/) to submit a complaint.

**Your Colorado Privacy Rights**
--------------------------------

If you are a resident of Colorado, you have the right under the Colorado Privacy Act (CPA), upon a verified request, to:

* Opt-out from the use of personal data for targeted advertising and certain types of profiling.
* Know whether a controller is collecting personal data.
* Access personal data that a controller has collected about you.
* Correct personal data.
* Delete personal data if applicable by Federal law.
* Download and remove personal data from a platform in a format that allows the transfer to another platform.
* Exercise your rights under the CPA without discrimination.

We collect, use, and share personal information as described in our main Privacy Policy. We will not collect, use, or share personal information in violation of the CPA.

We take reasonable measures to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. For more details on how we secure your data, please refer to our main Privacy Policy.

**If you have any questions or concerns regarding our compliance with the Colorado Privacy Act (CPA), please contact us at: [sales@sdbullion.com](mailto:sales@sdbullion.com). Please also refer to our main Privacy Policy for additional information regarding the handling of your personal information. This CPA section should be read in conjunction with our main Privacy Policy, which provides a comprehensive overview of our data privacy practices.**

**Your Connecticut Privacy Rights**
-----------------------------------

If you are a resident of Connecticut, you have the right under the Connecticut Data Privacy Act, upon a verified request, to:

* Access personal data that a controller has collected about you.
* Correct inaccuracies in your personal data.
* Delete your personal data, including personal data that the controller collected through third parties if applicable by Federal law.
* Obtain a copy of your personal data in a portable and readily usable format that allows you to transfer the data to another controller with ease.
* Opt-out the processing of personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising, and profiling that may have a legal or other significant impact.

**Complaints of violations of the Connecticut Privacy Act may be submitted to the Connecticut Attorney General. The Attorney general has exclusive authority to enforce violations of the Act. For more information or questions regarding the CTDPA or collection of and/or processing of personal data please contact us at [sales@sdbullion.com](mailto:sales@sdbullion.com).**

**Your Utah Privacy Rights**
----------------------------

If you are a resident of Utah, you have the right under the Utah Consumer Privacy Act, upon a verified request, and as it pertains to data provided by you directly to the controller (not data obtained indirectly), to:

* Access data, including confirming whether a controller is processing their data, and the ability to request and receive that data.
* Deletion of personal data, if the data subject directly provided the data to the controller and if applicable by Federal law.
* Portability, obtaining a copy of their personal data that they provided to the controller, in a format that is portable to a technically reasonable extent, readily usable to a practical extent, and enables the consumer to transmit the data to another controller reasonably easily, where the processing is carried out by automated means.
* Opt out of certain processing, specifically for the purposes of targeted advertising.

For additional information regarding the collection and processing of personal data, refer to the main privacy policy above. For questions regarding the Utah Consumer Privacy Act or our collection and/or processing of personal data please contact us at sales@sdbullion.com. 

Under Utah law, the UCPA does not provide the right of action, the ability for a consumer to sue a controller for noncompliance or a data breach. Consumers may also not use a violation of the UCPA to support a claim under other Utah laws.

****Children's Privacy****
--------------------------

Our Services and Site are not directed at children under 18 years of age, and we do not knowingly collect or receive Personal Information from them. If we learn that we have received Personal Information from a child who is under 18, we will delete the data. If you believe that we have received Personal Information from a child under the age of 18, you may contact us at sales@sdbullion.com. 

****Do Not Track Signals****
----------------------------

Our Site currently does not respond to “Do Not Track” (DNT) signals and operates as described in this Notice, whether or not a DNT signal is received.

****Changes To This Privacy Notice****
--------------------------------------

We may change this Privacy Notice at any time. We will post all changes to this Privacy Notice on this page and will indicate at the top of the page the modified notice's effective date. We therefore encourage you to refer to this page on an ongoing basis so that you are aware of our current privacy notice. If required by the applicable law, we will notify you if the changes. By continuing to use the Site and/or the Services or providing us with information following such a replacement Notice being uploaded, you agree that you will be deemed to have agreed to be bound by the Privacy Notice as changed.

****SMS****
-----------

1. If you decide to opt in to SMS text messaging from SD Bullion, we will send marketing messages of exclusive offers, discounts and other marketing related messages.
2. You can cancel the SMS service at any time. Just text "STOP" to the short code provided. After you send the SMS message "STOP" to us, we will send you an SMS message to confirm that you have been unsubscribed. After this, you will no longer receive SMS messages from us. If you want to join again, just sign up as you did the first time and we will start sending SMS messages to you again.
3. If you are experiencing issues with the messaging program you can reply with the keyword HELP for more assistance, or you can get help directly at sales@sdbullion.com or 1-800-294-8732.
4. Carriers are not liable for delayed or undelivered messages
5. As always, message and data rates may apply for any messages sent to you from us and to us from you. You may receive messages every week. If you have any questions about your text plan or data plan, it is best to contact your wireless provider.
6. If you have any questions regarding privacy, please read our terms of service, please click [here](https://sdbullion.com/terms-use).

****User Reviews/Generated Content****
--------------------------------------

User reviews are the opinion of others and are not the opinion of SD Bullion, Inc. SD Bullion, Inc accepts no responsibility for the opinions of other users. Furthermore, User Generated Content may be published, used in adverts, shared or hosted on third party websites associated with SD Bullion. Reviews can also be visible in public areas at SDBullion.com to all visitors. You knowingly acknowledge SD Bullion does not guarantee confidentiality with respect to any User Generated Content submitted through SDBullion.com or affiliated third parties that SDBullion.com may use to collect said User Generated Content.

****Contact Us****
------------------

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this Privacy Notice, please contact us at:

SD Bullion, Inc  
PO Box 8766

Toledo, OH 43623  
sales@sdbullion.com  
1(800)294-8732

   loading="lazy" />

CALL US

EMAIL US

Email Address   Submit

### GET THE INSIDE SCOOP!

The best bullion deals straight to your inbox.

EASY PAYMENT OPTIONS

CUSTOMER CARE

RESOURCES

  © 2024 SD Bullion, Inc. All rights reserved.
